Kelly Money, M.A.

kellylmoney@protonmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellymoney/

I am a data analyst with extensive experience working with Excel, R, SQL, Domo, and Tableau. Data wrangling is totally my jam. I enjoy creating tools for reproducible data cleaning and visualization. I love using data to answer questions and solve problems!

Professional Status

DATA ANALYST III | UTAH COUNTY GOVERNMENT | MARCH 2023 - CURRENT

- Develop, implement, test, calibrate, and maintain models in system applications to predict market values of real property
- Write and maintain data dictionaries for databases, including functionality, tables, attributes, and relationships
- Write and maintain documentation for functionality and code for all created R Shiny applications that are used during real property valuation
- Prepare, format, validate, and maintain sales information for sales ratio studies and market modeling applications
- Write and maintain support documentation for all valuation processes
- Work with other departments to define data requirements for statistical analysis
- Utilize geographic information systems (GIS) and R Shiny applications to create and review real property visualizations
- Train Data Analyst I/II in property valuations and software applications

Education

B.S INFORMATION SYSTEMS – BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE | UTAH VALLEY UNIVERSITY

CERTIFICATE OF PROFICIENCY - DATABASE ADMINISTRATION AND DATA WAREHOUSING | UTAH VALLEY UNIVERSITY

CERTIFICATE OF PROFICIENCY - DATA ANALYTICS | UTAH VALLEY UNIVERSITY

CERTIFICATE OF PROFICIENCY - INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY | UTAH VALLEY UNIVERSITY

M.A. COMPOSITION RHETORIC/ENGLISH | MISSOURI STATE UNIVERSITY

B.A. ENGLISH | MISSOURI STATE UNIVERSITY

Prior Experience

PERFORMANCE MARKETING ANALYST | FILEVINE, INC | JULY 2022 – MARCH 2023

- · Use R to create weekly audits of all data coming in through lead generation channels
- Audit performance marketing data, surface any discrepancies or problems, and create a robust reporting engine
- Collaborate with other team members to refine metrics and attribute definitions for company-wide adherence
- Work with members of the Performance Marketing team to create both high level and granular reports from the marketing and sales data to improve and refine business focus and activities.
- Create and present predictive analyses reports in R
- Work with stakeholders to collaborate on decision-making and create actionable recommendations
- · Track campaign metrics and make recommendations to improve campaign spending effectiveness
- Combine datasets to surface new insights about marketing campaigns and spending
- Effectively communicate recommendations based on analysis

DATA OPERATIONS CONSULTANT | FILEVINE, INC | OCTOBER 2020 – JULY 2022

- Cleaning, transforming, and mapping and migrating data using R and Excel
- Assist in planning and managing the data migration process
- Responsible for meeting with stakeholders to discuss and understand their current data software and what their data requirements will be going forward
- · Responsible for auditing existing data and addressing errors while also triaging any issues that arose during implementation
- · Responsible for cleaning, mapping, and aligning data to effectively move data between software
- Make recommendations to address implementation needs as well as assess technical feasibility

DATA ANALYST | UTAH VALLEY UNIVERSITY | JANUARY 2019 - OCTOBER 2020

- Data reporting using business intelligence tools (i.e., Tableau workbooks and dashboard design)
- Data collecting, analyzing, tracking methods and techniques
- Verifying, cleaning, and understanding of research data (SQL)
- Thorough understanding of privacy and compliance issues regarding personal data
- Automated data cleaning with a Shiny App for University College at UVU

Skills & Abilities

Programming Languages: SQL, Bash, R

Software: Microsoft Office Suite, Tableau, Domo, ArcGIS

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux **Databases:** MSSQL Server, Oracle, Azure

Other: Technical writing for employee documentation